

- **)** +20 109 699 3853
- www.johnydev.com
- Cairo, Egypt.

### **COVER LETTER**

#### DEAR SIR / MADAM,

My name is John, I am a DevOps Engineer offering 9 years of experience, an expert in Windows OS, MAC OSX & Linux, with a strong development background.

My target is to master the DevOps culture, currently I am focusing on Corontainerization Orchestration, CI /CD and Cloud services.

My previous roles in the IT field started with providing level 1 and level 2 technical support as a Sr. System Administrator, troubleshooting, and maintenance of the technology infrastructure and systems for endpoint device management Including win-servers (2003, 2008, 2012), Mac server, firewall Linux server, Render Farm, network management, NAS, SAN, LAN, WAN, RAID, ticketing systems, software distribution, updates, patching virus protection, and imaging.

Then I became an IT Project Manager, which was more managerial level than technical Starting with determine project objectives, predict resources needed, assign tasks, monitor project pipeline until delivered on time, during this time i was preparing myself to be a DevOps engineer.

And currently I am a DevOps Engineer responsible for the CI/CD process however am participating in the project Code and Build as well.

Besides my main experience in the IT field, I have been using Adobe Products as a hobby to design for the past 12 years and Front-End for the past 5 years, I am not a Graphic Designer but I have a quite good taste and freelance experience doing different kind of designs, video editing, and websites, you are welcome to check my website <a href="https://www.johnydev.com">www.johnydev.com</a>

I have enclosed my cover letter for your review. I appreciate your time.

Sincerely,

John Bedeir DevOps Engineer







# **JOHN BEDEIR** DevOps Engineer

+20 109 699 3853

 $\bowtie$ john.bedeir@gmail.com

www.johnydev.com

Cairo, Egypt.

#### ₾ Summary

I am a DevOps Engineer offering 9 years of experience, an expert in Linux, Windows OS & MAC OSX with a strong development background.

Plus a quite good experience in Web Design and Development.

# Career Objective

Currently, I am focusing on Python, Containers & Cloud Services and my aim is to master DevOps & Automation.

# Sr. Sys Admin

# Linux Sys Admin

# Python

# DevOps

# Automation

# Work Experiences

# Jan 2020 - Current

# **DevOps Engineer**

### **Orange Business Services**

Cairo, Egypt

Orange is a French multinational telecommunication corporation.

- Containerize Applications
- Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery
- Working on ways to automate reports, improve development and release processes
- Working in Software developmen life cycle
- Working in AGILE.
- · Front-End Development.
- Project 1: Adjusting an Admin Portal Front-End
- Project 2: Building an Admin Portal Front-End
- Project 3: Building CI / CD for a web application
- Project 4: Build, Test, Release, Deploy for a web application

# Expertise

Linux, Windows & MAC

Docker

**Bash Scripting** 

Vmware, Parrallels & Virtualbox

Git

Web Hosting

HTML5 / CSS3

#### Sep 2018 - Sep 2019 IT PROJECT MANAGER

#### **Yaryor Technologies**

## Dubai, UAE

YARYOR is a small company, mostly working on projects that include new technologies like Robotics, Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Digital Signage, Web Development, and Mobile applications.

- IT Manager
- Determine and define project scope and objectives
- · Predict resources needed to reach objectives
- Measure project performance to identify areas for improvement
- Web Development: Front-End & Adobe XD

#### Mar 2016 - Apr 2018 SR. SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

#### Plus500 BG

### ▼ Sofia, Bulgaria

Plus500 is a huge international firm providing online trading, working there was a great opportunity I started there with the Technical Support team then I got promoted to Senior IT providing High-level Support for Windows OS in two offices.

- Provide 24/7 Level 2 Support across all facilities.
- Ensure that helpdesk tickets are closed or escalated promptly.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Symantec endpoint console.
- Monitoring the Server room temperature via sensor.

# Languages

Arabic	Native
English	Fluent
Bulgarian	Conversational
Bulgarian	Conversational

- Performs other related duties as assigned.

# Work Experiences

### Jan 2014 - Jul 2015

### SR. SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

#### **Aroma Studios**



AROMA is an extraordinary company for media production in the middle east, I got the opportunity for working as a Senior IT with a team of IT providing 24/7 coverage with level 2 crossover platform support Windows OS, Mac OSX, and Linux.

- Level 1 2 Support for all instance (on location, via phone & remotely)
- Install and configure linux and perform system maintenance.
- Ensure pending tasks have been solved.
- Check Kaspersky endpoint security management console and ensure there are no alerts.
- Check the Servers & Renderfarm room temperature.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned

# Sep 2011 - Dec 2013 SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

### Arabcomed



The Arab Company for Medical Products is a factory for manufacturing pharmaceutical this was my first full-time job after graduation providing level 1 help desk support and Create new designs and editing the company website.

- · Level 1 Support on location, via phone or remotely,
- Create New Designs for the next coming product
- Ensure all the endpoint devices are working properly.
- Check the Server room temperature.



# **Education and Certificates**

2015 - 2019

Masters in Computer Science and Engineering

Technical University, Sofia, Bulgaria.

2007 - 2011

**Bachelors in Computer Science** 

Future Academy, Cairo, Egypt.

Volunteering Activity

Member of IT Committee

Enactus Organization, Cairo, Egypt.

# **CERTIFICATES & SELF-STUDIES**

AWS	(Self-Study)
Kubernetes	(Self-Study)
Jenkins	(Self-Study)
Ansible	(Self-Study)
Vagrant	(Self-Study)
Python	(Self-Study)
RHCSA	(Self-Study)
JavaScript	(Self-Study)
MCSA	(Self-Study)
ICDL	(Certified)

# OTHER SKILLS & **APPS**

Ubuntu, Mint & CentOs

Apache, Nginx, WAMP, **XAMPP** 

FLASK, REST API, SOAP **OpenCV** 

MYSQL, MongoDB

Remote Apps & **PDQ Deploy** 

WDS & NetInstall

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesigns

**Adobe After Effects** 

Adobe XD

Adobe Photoshop (Certified)

